aupairworld.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy policy - AuPairWorld

Last modified: 26.07.2018

Previous version of AuPairWorld's privacy policy

**Data protection information for visitors to the website**

We, AuPairWorld GmbH, Johanna-Waescher-Str. 7 34131, Kassel/Germany, Tel.: +49 (0) 561 31 0561 - 0, [info@aupairworld.com](mailto:info@aupairworld.com) set out below which of your data we process on this website. Should you have any questions relating to data protection, our data protection officer would be happy to respond at datenschutz@dsb-moers.de.

**Purpose, legal basis, categories of recipients, storage period for the data processing**

_Purpose: Presentation of the company and provision of services and/or sale of products, as well as communication through the Internet_

The purpose of data processing on this website is to provide information about the products and services of our company, combined with the opportunity for users to be able to make contact with the appropriate contact person in house.

  * Art. 6 (1)(a) GDPR for the processing of personal data with the consent of the data subject.

  * Art. 6 (1)(b) GDPR for the processing of personal data necessary for the performance of a contract with the data subject, as well as for taking appropriate steps prior to entering into a contract.

  * Art. 6 (1)(c) GDPR for the processing necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject in accordance with applicable EU law or in accordance with the applicable law of a country in which the GDPR is applicable in whole or in part.

  * Art. 6 (1)(f) GDPR for the processing of personal data necessary to protect the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject. Legitimate interests are, in particular, our commercial interest to be able to provide our website, the security of information, the enforcement of our own legal claims and the compliance with further legislation.

To this end, in the context of service provision, we use service providers that have been separately bound to maintain confidentiality and to protect data. Data shall only be disclosed to a third party in the existence of overriding statutory provisions. No data is transmitted to third countries.

When you visit the website, a connection is established with your browser. The information collected, which is listed below, is stored in temporary system files and recorded automatically: IP address of your device, data and time of access, name and URL of files accessed, website from which access is initiated or from which you are directed to our site (referrer URL), browser used and, where applicable, the operating system of your device, as well as the name of your provider.

The data specified is processed by us for the purpose of seamlessly establishing a connection and for system security. The connection data created is automatically deleted and is not retained for more than seven days. If the website is used improperly, log files, which need to be retained for evidence purposes, are saved until the incident is clarified.

_Use of cookies_

This website uses so-called “cookies”, or text files, which are stored on your computer and which enable your use of the website to be analysed.

The information produced by the cookie about the way you use this website is used to analyse visitor behaviour on the website and to improve our information offering. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1)(f) GDPR (legitimate interests). The optimisation of the web presence constitutes such a legitimate interest. The information gained is only used for internal statistical analysis and is not passed on to third parties.

The cookies are removed after 2 years. You can prevent cookies from being saved by changing the appropriate setting in your browser software; however, we would like to point out that in this case you would not be able to use all the features of this website to their full extent.

Data is collected anonymously; the data collected cannot be related to you.

_Adwords Conversion Tracking_

If you reached our website via a Google advertisement, a cookie will be placed on your computer via Google Adwords Conversion Tracking. It remains valid for 30 days. To the extent you visit certain AuPair World pages whilst the cookie is valid, both we and Google are able to see that you have clicked on the ad and were directed to the site. In this manner, we learn how many users have clicked on our advertisements. You may prevent the recording of this data by deactivating the automatic placement of cookies in your browser settings for <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>. Data protection information from Google on conversion tracking may be found [here](http://services.google.com/sitestats/en.html "Go to the page").

_Contact_ _form_ __  
Should you wish to write to us using our contact from, your data from the form is processed to deal with your concern. The legal basis for the transmission of data to us is Art. 6 (1)(a) GDPR. You may withdraw your consent under data protection law at any time with effect for the future.  
The data is then removed. If there is no legal obligation to retain data arising from your enquiry (e.g. an order), the data is removed after three years.  
Your data is transmitted internally to the competent contact person to process your enquiry. Data is not transmitted to a third party without your approval.

_Customer account / contractual services_  
If you order products and/or services through the website, we process your data (name, address, contact details, payment details, where applicable) for the purpose of contract fulfilment. The legal basis is Art. 6 (1)(b) GDPR. The data is only disclosed to third parties if required to meet the purpose of the contract. The data is removed at the end of the tax retention period of 10 years following the preparation of the annual financial statement and the end of the calendar year. The data is stored in the user account for as long as the customer account exists.

_Payments with Paypal_

If you choose the payment option with Paypal, we will transmit the data for contract processing (legal basis is art. 6 par. 1 lit. b DSGVO) to Paypal (PayPal (Europe) S.à r.l. et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg). The data protection regulations of Paypal apply are available here: https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full?locale.x=en_EN

_Payments with Concardis_

If you choose the payment option with Concardis, we will transfer the data for contract processing (legal basis is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b DSGVO) to Concardis GmbH (ConCardis GmbH, Helfmann-Park 7, 65760 Eschborn). Concardis' privacy policy is available here: https://www.concardis.com/datenschutzerklaerung

_Analysis of user behaviour after your registration_

After your registration, we collect your IP address as well as the time of your registration in addition to the data you have entered. With your registration you agree that we will evaluate your data. This is necessary in order to be able to continue to offer AuPairWorld's high quality services. For this purpose we compare the data you have entered with other data freely accessible on the Internet. This allows us to identify unwanted entries (frivolous and unlawful entries, agencies etc.). However, AuPairWorld does not accept guarantees for the quality of the entries. The legal basis for data processing is Article 6 (1) lit. (b) GDPR; Data processing is necessary for the implementation of the purpose.

_Newsletter and E-Mail-Tracking_

The purpose of sending the newsletter is to provide information about new products and services from our company. Your consent is required for subscription to the newsletter, the legal basis for the data processing is Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR. Data is not transmitted to third parties. The so-called “double opt-in process” is used when subscribing to the newsletter. You must actively confirm the request for the newsletter again by clicking on the link in the email sent to you. You may unsubscribe at any time by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link. You can also send us an unsubscribe request by email to the aforementioned address.

We use a so-called tracking pixel in order to be able to make statements about the usage of e-mails sent by AuPairWorld. This tracking pixel enables the user behaviour to be evaluated anonymously. The information that is evaluated is the date and time the e-mail was opened or deleted. It is not possible to connect this information to you. Legal basis is your consent acc. to Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit. A GDPR. You can rescind the processing of this data at any time with effect for the future. To do so, please e-mail us at: [support@aupairworld.com](mailto:support@aupairworld.com?subject=Email%20tracking).

_Hotjar_  
This website uses the web analysis service Hotjar. Hotjar is a European company headquartered in Malta (Hotjar Ltd, Level 2, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta, Europe). We use Hotjar to analyse movement on our website, for example, mouse movements, scrolling, button clicks. So-called heat maps are produced as a result. Using these heat maps, we are able to optimise the website and improve the user experience. We can also get direct user feedback and improve customer orientation even further. Legal basis for the data processing are our legitimate interests relating to the optimisation of our website in accordance with Art. 6 (1)(f) GDPR. Data security is ensured by an order process agreement with Hotjar Ltd. The following data is collected through Hotjar:

\- Mouse tracks,  
\- Button clicks,  
\- Screen scrolling,  
\- Anonymised IP address,  
\- Size of the visitor’s screen,  
\- Type of device (Smartphone, Computer) and browser used,  
\- Visitor’s country,  
\- Language settings configured.

You can turn off tracking by Hotjar by enabling the “Do Not Track” header in your browser. These settings can be made in all current browsers.  
Please remember to make these settings on all the devices you use to visit our website. If you have already made these settings, your visit is not tracked by Hotjar. For more information about data protection at Hotjar, please read Hotjar's privacy statement at https://www.hotjar.com/privacy.  
Instructions for the “Do Not Track” settings can be found at <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>

_Matomo (formerly PIWIK)_  
We use Matomo software to analyse and statistically evaluate the use of our website. The legal basis is Art 6 (1) lit f. GDPR with respect to the needs-based design and optimisation of the website. These interests are legitimate in the context of Art. 6 (1) lit f. GDPR. Cookies are used for tracking with the Piwik application. The information produced by the cookie about the use of the website is transmitted to our server and collated in pseudonymous usage profiles. The information is used to analyse the use of the website and to ensure that our website is designed based on user needs. The information is not passed on to third parties. At no stage is the IP address connected to other data relating to the user. The IP addresses are anonymised so that attribution is not possible (IP masking).  
Opt-out: [https://matomo.aupairworld.com/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut&language=en](https://matomo.aupairworld.com/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut&language=en "Opt-out")

_Integration of YouTube_  
We use YouTube to embed videos (legal basis in accordance with Art. 6 (1)(f) GDPR with the operation of our website and the consideration of the interests of the parties concerned by disabling the tracking function in the YouTube code). Google Ireland Ltd. has committed to ensuring appropriate data protection in accordance with the American-European and the American-Swiss privacy shield. More information can be found in Google’s comprehensive privacy statement https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/, Opt-out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

_Google ReCaptcha_  
We use Google ReCaptcha to protect against bots on the basis of our legitimate interest pursuant to Art. 6 (1)(f) GDPR. Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, 4 Barrow St, Dublin, D04 E5W5, Irland, has committed to ensuring appropriate data protection in accordance with the American-European and the American-Swiss privacy shield. More information can be found in Google’s comprehensive privacy statement https://www.google.com/policies/privacy. You can opt out via your Google account: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

_Integration of videos via Wistia_  
We use Wistia, a service of Wistia Inc., 17 Tudor Street Cambridge, Massachusetts, 02139 USA to embed/ store videos. The legal basis for data processing are our legitimate interests in accordance with Art. 6 (1)(f) GDPR with the operation of our website and taking into account the interests of the parties concerned. The security of the processing is also ensured inter alia by an EU standard agreement.

**Your right to information, rectification, deletion, object and data portability**

You may avail yourself of your right to information, rectification and deletion of data at any time. Simply contact us using one of the methods described above. Should you require data to be deleted, which we are still legally obligated to retain, access to your data will be restricted (blocked). The same applies to an appeal. You may avail yourself of your right to data portability if the recipient and ourselves have the technical means. 

**Right of appeal**

You have the option at any time to lodge an appeal with a data protection supervisory authority.

**Data security / encryption**

This website uses “Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure” (https). The connection between your browser and our server is encrypted.

**Currency of and changes to this privacy statement**

We reserve the right to change the content of this privacy statement at any time. This is usually done if the services used are subject to further development or adaptation. You can view the current privacy statement on our website. Date of this statement: 26.07.2018

#### Further privacy statements

Further privacy statements can be found here.
